Guide to the Richard W. Gilkey Photographs 1947-2005
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
- Oregon Stater, 1948-2005; Series XI; 263 photographs
  - Marlyn Melson, PuO-054; 9 negatives (Box 2)
  - Friday Night Activities Homecoming, 1949; PuO-055; 5 negatives (Box 2)
  - Saturday Activities Homecoming, 1949; PuO-056; 7 negatives (Box 2)
  - Governor McKay at Homecoming Banquet, 1949; PuO-057 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Promotion Committee, 1949; PuO-058 (Box 2)
  - Card Section at WSC Game, 1949; PuO-059; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Drum Majorettes, PuO-060; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Rooting Section, 1949; PuO-061; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Stain Glass Background for December 1949 cover, PuO-062; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Foreground for December 1949 cover, PuO-063; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Commencement, 1949; PuO-068 - PuO-071; 4 negatives (Box 2)
    Images PuO-068 and PuO-069 of graduates gathering in Memorial Union for procession available online.
  - Basketball game in Gill Coliseum, 1950; PuO-072 - PuO-073; 2 negatives and 1 print (Box 2)
    PuO-072 published on cover of February 1950 issue.
    - PuO-072, oversize print (Box 4)
    - PuO-072 - PuO-073, negatives (Box 2)
  - Nursery School, 1950; PuO-074 (Box 2)
    Cover of March 1950 issue.
  - McDonald Room, PuO-075; 1 negative and 1 print (Box 2-3)
  - Power Lab in Dearborn, PuO-075 (Box 2)
  - Dean Gleeson, PuO-076; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Switchboard in Power Lab, PuO-077 (Box 2)
  - Classroom in Dearborn, PuO-078 (Box 2)
  - Graduate Lab, PuO-078 (Box 2)
  - Senior Day, 1950; PuO-079 (Box 2)
  - Avery Park Canoe, 1950; PuO-080 - PuO-081; 6 negatives (Box 2)
    PuO-080 published on May 1950 cover.
  - Sackett Hall Open House, PuO-082; 9 negatives (Box 2)
  - Senior Day Activities Lower Campus, PuO-083; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Senior Day Educational Exhibit, PuO-084; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Commencement, 1950; PuO-085 (Box 2)
    June 1950 cover.
  - Museum in Coliseum, PuO-086 (Box 2)
  - Slats Gill Office, PuO-087 (Box 2)
  - Visual Aid Office, PuO-088 (Box 2)
  - Storage Room in Coliseum, PuO-089 (Box 2)
  - Athletic Office in Coliseum, PuO-090 (Box 2)
  - Shower Room in Coliseum, PuO-091 (Box 2)
  - Bell Field (South Stands), PuO-092 - POU-093 (Box 2)
  - Bell Field (Press Box), PuO-094 (Box 2)
  - Bell Field (Extension), PuO-095 (Box 2)
  - Bell Field (Entrance Ramp), PuO-096 (Box 2)
  - Stadium Drive Sign at Bell Field, PuO-097; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Old John Feature Story Picture, 1951; PuO-099 (Box 2)
  - Two Oregon State graduates, Dean Blair and Joan Aune., 1951; PuO-100 - PuO-101; 5 negatives (Box 2)
    Published on cover of June 1951 Oregon Stater.
  - OSC Promotions, PuO-102; 7 negatives (Box 2)
  - Two students walking in Memorial Union quad, 1952; PuO-107; 5 negatives (Box 2)
    Published on cover of February 1952 Oregon Stater.
  - Kathie Raffeto, 1952; PuO-112 (Box 2)
  - Play Born Yesterday with Kathie Raffetto, 1952; PuO-113 and PuO-115 (Box 2)
  - Born Yesterday, 1952; PuO-116 - PuO-119; 23 negatives (Box 2)
  - Born Yesterday Kathie Raffetto, PuO-120; 8 negatives (Box 2)
  - Theodore Yerian, PuO-123 (Box 2)
  - Roland Eugene Dimick, PuO-125 (Box 2)
  - W.F. McCulloch, PuO-127 (Box 2)
  - Donald D. Hill, PuO-129 (Box 2)
  - Edwin Arthur Yunker, PuO-131 (Box 2)
  - Eva Blackwell, PuO-134 (Box 2)
  - Marie Diedesch, PuO-136 (Box 2)
  - William E.Milne, PuO-138 (Box 2)
  - Fred O. McMillan, PuO-141 (Box 2)
  - Sigma Chi House Mother, 1951; PuO-144; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Tables in Front of Memorial Union, PuO-145; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Oregon Stater Cover Series, 1952-2005; 9 prints
    Photographs taken in 1952-1953; prints made in 2005.
    - Eva Blackwell (Box 4)
    - Marie Diedesch (Box 4)
    - Roland Eugene Dimick (Box 4)
    - Donald D. Hill (Box 4)
    - W.F. McCulloch (Box 4)
    - Fred O. McMillan (Box 4)
    - William E. Milne (Box 4)
    - Theodore Yerian (Box 4)
    - Edwin Arthur Yunker (Box 4)
- News Bureau, 1948-1951; Series XII; 75 photographs
  Series XII consists of photographs taken by Gilkey for the Oregon State News Bureau and includes publicity images of athletes, coaches, and athletic events as well as students and student activities.
  - Ex-Giantonians on OSC Basketball Team, 1948; PuNB-001 - PuNB-002; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Richards, 1948; PuNB-003; 2 negatives
    - Baseball publicity photo (Box 2)
    - Baseball publicity photo (Box 2)
  - Clarence (Chuck) Sauvain, 1948; PuNB-004 (Box 2)
    Baseball player.
  - Carl Harry Gustafson, 1948; PuNB-005 (Box 2)
  - Frank Roelandt, 1948; PuNB-006; 2 negatives
    - Baseball publicity photo (Box 2)
    - Baseball publicity photo (Box 2)
  - Bob Christianson, first baseman., 1948; PuNB-007 (Box 2)
  - Colar, 1948; PuNB-008; 2 negatives
    - Baseball publicity photo (Box 2)
    - Baseball publicity photo (Box 2)
  - PCC Wrestling Champions, 1948; PuNB-009; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Pub. for State Track Meet, 1948; PuNB-010; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Reg. for State Track Meet, 1948; PuNB-011; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Honor Grads in Pharmacy, 1948; PuNB-012 (Box 2)
  - Re-Turfing Bell Field, 1948; PuNB-013 - PuNB-0015; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Spring Football Game, 1948; PuNB-016; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Spring Football Practice, 1949; PuNB-017; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Kip Taylor, Bump Elliot, Slats Gill, PuNB-018; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Jim Dixon and Kip Taylor, PuNB-019; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - OSC Baseball Varsity Pitching Staff, 1949; PuNB-020; 2 negatives (Box 2)
    Gerald John ("Rick") Erickson, Kenneth Leroy Carpenter, Robert Henry Stolz, and Chuck Sauvin. Published in May 1949 Oregon Stater. One image available online.
  - Barometer Night Staff for Preview, PuNB-021; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Pat Vaughn drinking soda, PuNB-022; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Chapter Room Theta House, PuNB-023; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Pat Vaughn in Front of Memorial Union, PuNB-024; 5 negatives (Box 2)
  - Pat Vaughn, Memorial Union Background, PuNB-025 - PuNB-0026; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sharon Langdon, PuNB-027; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Vic Smith, Kip Taylor, PuNB-028; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Coaching Staff Eating Duck After Oregon Game, 1949; PuNB-040; 3 negatives and 1 digital print (Box 2-3)
  - Modern Dance, PuNB-045 - PuNB-0050; 10 negatives (Box 2)
  - Spec Keene and two others, PuNB-057 (Box 2)
  - Rally girls cheer team to victory at Oregon-Oregon State football game, 1950; PuNB-058 (Box 2)
    Photographer kneeling in foreground. Published in 1951 Beaver yearbook, p. 112 and as image for 2005 exhibit poster.
- Campus Buildings, circa 1950; Series XIII; 33 photographs
  Series XIII includes images of the exteriors and interiors of several campus buildings.
  - Trees along 35th St, PA-011 (Box 2)
  - Pharmacy Building, PA-014 (Box 2)
  - Benton Hall, PA-015 (Box 2)
  - Smoke Stack, PA-016 (Box 2)
  - Benton Hall, PA-016 - PA-017; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Front of Memorial Union, PA-029; 8 negatives (Box 2)
  - Memorial Union Infrared, PA-030 (Box 2)
  - Ceiling of Memorial Union, PA-031 (Box 2)
  - Reference Room of Library, PA-032; 1 negative and 1 print (Box 2-3)
  - Memorial Union Entrance with Statue, PA-033 (Box 2)
  - Library, PA-034; 2 negatives and 2 prints (Box 2-3)
  - Withycombe Hall, PA-035; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Chemistry Building, PA-036 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture Hall, PA-037 (Box 2)
  - Commerce Hall, PA-038 (Box 2)
  - Home Economics Wing, PA-039; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Benton Hall, PA-040 (Box 2)
- Campus Views, circa 1950; Series XIV; 11 photographs
  The campus views include several images of campus buildings and views after a snowstorm. The Corvallis landscape images were taken from a high point, perhaps Bald Hill.
  - Trees on Lower Campus, PL-009 (Box 2)
  - Memorial Union in snow, PL-017 - PL-019; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Library in snow, PL-020; 1 negative and 1 print (Box 2)
  - Snow in Memorial Union quadrangle from roof of Memorial Union, PL-021 - PL-023; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Corvallis landscape, PL-034; 2 negatives (Box 2)
- Unnumbered Color Transparencies, 1949; Series XV; 15 photographs
  Series XV consists of color transparencies of Oregon State College campus buildings and views, including construction of Gill Coliseum, and several images of Oregon State student, Marlyn Melson, at the Memorial Union.
  - Gill Coliseum Construction, circa 1949; 5 transparencies and 1 digital print (Box 2-3)
  - Benton Hall (Box 2)
  - Education Hall (Box 2)
  - Kidder Hall (Box 2)
  - Campus View (Box 2)
  - Marlyn Melson at Memorial Union, 1949; 5 transparencies (Box 2-3)
    Published on cover of May 1949 Oregon Stater.
- Documentary Materials, 1947-2005; Series XVI
  Series XVI consists of documentary materials that include Gilkey's photographs, materials from the 2005 exhibit of Gilkey's photographs prepared by the Oregon State University Archives, and the original paper negative sleeves. The publication, Paste Up at "State" was published by Oregon State students as a pictorial magazine in November 1948. Paul E. Lee was editor and director; Richard Gilkey was photographer. Only one issue was published. It includes features on student social activities. The compact discs include images used in the 2005 exhibit of Gilkey photographs and in Gilkey's presentation during the Alumni Association's Golden Jubilee Reunion celebration in June 2005.
  - PS Paste Up at "State", A Postscript from Oregon State College, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Scanned images for exhibit and presentation, 2005; 2 compact discs (Box 3)
  - Exhibit poster and text panel, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Original negative sleeves, 1947-1952 (Box 5)